# Jimmy M. Musangali

P.O. Box 155 - 80113 MARIAKANI, KENYA +254 707 542 115/+254 101 542 115

jmusangali@gmail.com

#### **Professional Profile**

Jimmy Musangali is currently The Pioneer General Manager of Sultan Palace Beach Resort, Kikambala- Kenya. He earned his Master's in Business Administration (MBA) from the University of Phoenix, USA. He holds a BSc in Management and Marketing from Everest University, USA. Food and Beverage Service/Sales Advanced Certificate from The Kenya Utalii College, Nairobi, Kenya.

Jimmy has a track record of gaining greater efficiency from existing resources through leadership, planning, organizational, decision making and team building skills. He has over fifteen years of extensive international senior level management experience in these fields: Hospitality, Banking, Customer Relations, and Logistics Industries.

#### **Education and Training**

- Master's in Business Administration University of Phoenix, USA. May 2006
- **B.Sc. Management and Marketing -** Everest University, USA. May 2004
- Food and Beverage Service/Sales Advanced Kenya Utalii College September 1994

#### **Professional Experience**

Pioneer General Manager Sultan Palace Beach Resort Kikambala, Kenya 2022 July – Present

A refined version of luxury, this resort is a true emblem of holiday lifestyle on the Kenya Coast. From the artistic design of its signature beach front holiday homes and private scenic white sandy shores to its elegant club house, this award-winning resort is where unrivalled vacation experience and culture meet with renewed authentic Swahili style.

#### Responsible for:

Setting up operations, recruitment and marketing. Directing the opening development and progress of this luxurious resort. Implementing and developing of all key managerial positions, and managing effective recruitment and employee development

Country Manager- Kenya IHGA General Manger (Pre-Opening) Osotua Luxury Resort Naivasha: by ICON Naivasha, Kenya 2020 August – 2022 July

This wonderful property in Naivasha, Kenya has a wonderful future. Responsible for: Setting up operations, recruitment and marketing. Directing the opening development and progress of this luxurious resort. Implementing and developing of all key managerial positions, and managing effective recruitment and employee development

General Manger -Sunrise Beach Resort Dar Es Salam, Tanzania 2019 June – July 2020

Responsible for consistently delivering results that contributed to the mission and overall success of the hotel by accomplishing performance objectives linked to improving business revenues, improving business effectiveness and efficiencies/the value of the hotel's products and services to its customers, and delivering a return on investment to shareholders with success being measured against productivity, customer relations, professionalism, revenue management, financial management, people management, leadership, quality management, communication, safety and security.

Also responsible for effective planning, delegating, coordinating, staffing, organizing, and decision making to attain desirable profit for the unit.

Manager – Diani Sea Lodge Diani Beach, Ukunda Kenya 2018 May – 2019 May

Reporting to the Managing Director, ensured that all facets of hotel management and operations were moving towards the company's objectives through financial control, customer management, staff development, hotel maintenance, hospitality and food service delivery. Responsible for overall guest experience and profitability of the hotel

# Operations Manager – Mombasa Continental Resort Shanzu Beach, Mombasa Kenya 2016 April – 2017 December

Worked towards attaining the mission/vision and organizational culture of the hotel. Ensured efficient and effective hotel operational systems, processes and policies. Supported management reporting information flow and business processes, and organizational planning. Maintained proper care and control of the property, equipment and materials. Seek opportunities to maximize revenue for the hotel, ensured product and service quality, operational efficiency and guest satisfaction. Retained staff by developing and managing staff skills, talent and abilities. Participated in all other industry related functions that benefited the hotel. Supported and promoted marketing functions of the hotel.

Tenati Ltd Consultancy, training, and Business Process Outsourcing (BPO) Mombasa, Kenya 2015 September – Present

With over fifteen years of extensive international senior level management experience Jimmy offers unparalleled expertise to the hospitality, leisure and tourism industries by providing ideal strategic management, planning, and implementation solutions to hotel/restaurant owners, managers and investors. Our client list included:

- Plaza Beach Hotel, Bamburi Beach Kenya
- Il Covo Italian Restaurant, Bamburi Beach, Kenya
- Gasaro Hotel, Mtwapa, Kenya
- Milele Beach Hotel, Bamburi Beach, Kenya

General Manager - Lucky Trucking LLC Lake St Louis, MO, USA 2012 - 2015 April

Provided leadership to position the company at the forefront of the Industry. Developed strategic plans to advance the Company's mission and objectives. Promoted revenue, profitability, growth as an organization. Oversaw Company operations to ensure production efficiency, quality service, client retention and cost effective management of resources.

.

## Business Development Manager Bank of America-Orlando Florida, USA 2007-2012

Responsible for managing the Business Development Department; developed new deposits, loans and merchant business for a specific target market of small to medium size businesses and business professionals; ensured all activities ran smoothly and efficiently for the department; provided leadership, training and supervision to officers and other personnel within the region; provided a superior level of customer relations and service; and ensured compliance with Bank policies and procedures. I was also responsible for attaining departmental and Bank goals through active participation in sales management and officer call programs. Tracked and analyzed banking economic trends and made recommendations to directors. Performed supervisory duties of department staff, and coordinated staff coverage within Orlando, Florida, USA.

Financial Analyst Bank of America- Orlando Florida, USA 2005- 2007

Integrated revenue/expense analyses, projections, variance reports and presentations. Compiled and analyzed financial information for the organization. Created, analyzed and consolidated monthly, quarterly and annual reports and ensured financial information had been recorded accurately to the financial statements. Interacted with cross-functional teams to ensure accurate monthly, quarterly and annual sales and margin forecasts. Collaborated with Finance department to implement policies and procedures to fulfill financial SOP requirements. Performed monthly analysis comparing account reconciliations to the trial balance to identify any variances. Prepared and distributed monthly, quarterly and annual reporting to ensure financial reporting requirements

Food Service Administrator II University of Central Florida, Orlando Florida, USA 2004-2004

Food and Beverage Manager

Double Tree Hotel, Orlando Florida, USA
2001-2004

Lead Customer Service Representative. Disney World, Orlando, USA 1999-2000

## **Assistant Restaurant Manager**

The Stanley Hotel - Nairobi, Kenya (Five-star hotel and member of the Leading Hotels of the World) 1994-1998

## Server/Captain

Serena Hotel - Nairobi, Kenya (Five-star hotel and member of the Leading Hotels of the World) 1992-1994

#### Certification

#### **SAP-FICO**

- Accounts Payable & Accounts Receivable
- Asset Accounting & Special Purpose Ledger
- Bank Accounting & Consolidation
- Cost Element Accounting
- Activity Based Costing
- Product Cost Controlling
- Profitability Analysis

#### KENYA UTALII COLLEGE

- Food and Beverage Service and Sales (Basic Level)
- Food and Beverage Service and Sales (Advanced level)

#### TOURISM PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATION (TPA)

## Language skills

Proficient in written and spoken English Proficient in written and spoken Swahili

#### Referees

1. Robert Watson Group Chairman

ICON Hotels Group Africa Ltd

Cell: +44 785 072 5509

Email: chairman@iconhotelsafrica.com

# Caesar Waganagwa CEO/Owner Il Covo Italian Restaurant Bamburi Beach, Mombasa Cell phone +254 722 709 800 email:info@ilcovomombasa.com

3. Rajen Solanki
Managing Director
Sunrise Beach Resort
Dar Es Salam.
Tanzania
Cell phone: +255,787,7

Cell phone: +255 787 788 805 email:md@kishenent.co.tz

#### 4. Jessi Kimani

Managing Director Lucky Trucking LLC 1440 Tahoe Drive Florissant, MO. 63042, USA Cell phone: +1 314 622 4321

# 5. Sven Kampa

Director

Diani Sea Lodge & Diani Sea Resort

Cell phone: **0727 452 853** 

email:Sven.kampa@dianisea.com